# Bhanuka Dissanayake

Software Engineer with Full-Time Work Rights (Australia) 0481262023 | 14 Colonel St, Clayton VIC 3168

bhanuka.m.dissanavake@gmail.com | in/bhanuka-dissanavake | github | blog |portfolio

# Summary

Software Engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in diverse domains of finance, retail, eCommerce, and sports across various technologies with exposure to the full Software Development Life Cycle. Skilled in analyzing user requirements, designing, developing, testing, troubleshooting, and maintaining software, and tackling complex problems by following the best coding standards.

#### Skills

- Programming Languages: C#, Python, Java
- Technologies/Frameworks: .NET Core Web API, Django, Angular
- SQL databases: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL | ORMs: EF Core, Dapper
- Other: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, xUnit
- Cloud technologies, CI/CD: AWS Services, Azure, Docker, GitLab CI, Jenkins
- Engineering Practices: SOLID, Clean, Design Patterns, REST, Unit testing, Agile/Scrum, JIRA
- Source Code Control: Github, GitLab, Bitbucket, Subversion
- Soft Skills: Adaptability, Cross-functional Team Collaboration, Problem Solving, Documentation

# **Experience**

### Software Engineer Consultant, Simpology Australia | Corzent

Oct 2024 - Present

Stack - C#, .NET Core, Angular, Microsoft SQL Server, AWS, Bitbucket

- Contributing to one of Australia's leading end-to-end loan origination platforms.
- Engaged in user requirement analysis and planning tasks and technical specifications.
- Contributed to sub-status alert tracking for loan applications to improve monitoring and notifications.
- Developed features for digital income verifications, ensuring up-to-date and accurate data.

#### **Software Engineer, Calcey Technologies**

April 2022 - April 2024

Stack - C#, .NET Core, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, AWS services like AWS S3, AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, Redis caching, GitLab, Jira

Project Engagements, tasks & responsibilities.

- Praisal Resource Management Portal
  - Researched, designed, and developed the version 1.0 release of the Calcey Resource Management portal for resource, project, and client management as a .NET Developer.
  - Collaboratively involved in client engagements, facilitated requirement gatherings, and contributed to sprint planning, fostering efficient project execution.
  - Designed and implemented core domain entities in alignment with Domain-Driven Design principles, ensuring an optimized and robust database solution.
  - Designed and developed Web API adhering to CQRS, and Clean architecture guidelines, leading to streamlined development, system scalability, and maintainability.
- Nelly.com

- Engaged in product maintenance of one of Nordic's leading e-commerce platforms in fashion and accessories as a .NET full-stack developer with an offshore team in Sweden.
- Worked on a microservices-based system. Helped with the upkeep of multiple different APIs and services.
- Troubleshooted, debugged, and fixed issues with a complex stored procedure-based querying system to meet desired requirements.
- Implemented a solution to protect outlet product prices, preventing automatic changes to full price due to late orders.

#### AiSCOUT

- Contributed to a talent identification platform linking football players and scouts as a .NET Developer collaborating with the 40+ development team.
- Involved in designing and developing impactful features for the monolith REST API of mobile applications (player, scout, coach) such as endpoints, background tasks, and consumer services adhering to CQRS, Clean, and SOLID principles.
- Engaged in developing a content management system for internal use of AiScout, using Blazor WASM, streamlining content management processes, and improving internal operational efficiency for developers, testers, and other users.

### Stanford GSB eLearning platform

- Successfully upgraded the Django version from 1. x to 4.0, leading to complete testing and releases by leading the development team (4 people) as a Full-stack Developer.
- Took the responsibility of initiating the project and tasks in the early stages and maintained proper documentation and reporting.
- Guided, and mentored junior developers, used resources to get the tasks done, reviewed code, and monitored them.

## Software Engineer, Enactor Ltd

Feb 2021 - March 2022

Stack - JAVA, Maven, MySQL, Enactor DevTools, Subversion, Jenkins, Cucumber, Docker, Apache Zookeeper, Jira

- Researched & developed a feature for partial downloading of files of POS machines, ensuring efficient transmission, and accurate information.
- Implemented DNS names for device registration via QR codes in the Enactor Retail Platform's Estate Manager, enhancing the registration process with efficiency and innovation.
- Optimized the Enactor platform's performance with a distributed processing feature using Zookeeper, enabling real-time extraction and updates from diverse documents like system events, retail transactions, and device events.
- Contributed as a developer in the Customer Support & Development team, focusing on troubleshooting and resolving customer-reported issues and bugs.
- Automated functionalities within the Point of Sale application and APIs to enhance efficiency and streamline operations.

#### **Undergraduate Researcher, University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka**

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021

- Researched, designed, and developed a Microservices-based SaaS platform to aggregate, integrate, and visualize transportation data within urban areas. Supported by the AHEAD Operation of the Ministry of Higher Education, Sri Lanka funded by the World Bank.
- Led the team (3 people) on Integrating traffic and weather data for traffic volume forecasting.

- Developed algorithms using Python for the comparative analysis of ARIMAX, VAR, and LSTM models for multivariate time-series forecasting.
- Achieved nearly 91% accuracy in forecast traffic count for the next day using the VAR model.
- Developed and integrated a Traffic Forecasting service using the VAR model as a Web API within the existing microservices platform, enhancing predictive accuracy and efficiency.
- Contributed to the front-end development of the Analytics Dashboard with Angular.
- Stack: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Statsmodels, Flask, JAVA, SpringBoot, Angular

#### Intern - Technology, Virtusa(Pvt) Ltd

Jul 2019 - Dec 2019

Project Engagements, tasks & responsibilities.

#### SIBOS COLLATERAL

- Developed a message generator for SWIFT MT700 format for the purpose of generating datasets for training machine learning models.
- Developed a POC of the Named Entity Recognition model and REST API for extracting metadata, performing sentiment analysis on news articles, and providing average sentiment scores for specific named entities.
- o Stack: JAVA, Maven, Python, Keras, Tensorflow, Flask, MongoDB

#### DTS Insights

- Worked as a JAVA Full-stack developer in a microservices-based Enterprise Software Development Life cycle dashboarding and gamification platform.
- Conducted comprehensive research and developed a proof of concept for enhancing security using Spring Security, ensuring robust protection for web applications.
- Developed the Authentication microservice for JWT authentication to secure user sessions and protect REST APIs.
- Created UI components and backend services for Login screen functionalities, improving user account management and security.
- o Stack- JAVA, Spring Boot, React, MySQL, Elasticsearch, Jira

#### **Education**

BSc.(Hons) in Engineering Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering (Washington Accord Accredited) University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka Jan 2017 - July 2021

Awards and Achievements

GPA: 3.67/4.20

- Research Publication A Comparison of ARIMAX, VAR, and LSTM on Multivariate Short-Term Traffic Volume Forecasting at 28th Conference of The Open Innovations Association FRUCT.[Link].
- Dean's List awards (Semesters 6 & 8) for outstanding academic performances from the University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka.
- Tech Blogger in Medium.com <u>bhanukadissanayake.medium.com</u> Writer at Towards Data Science, DataDriven Investor & Level Up Coding for quality blog content.
- Mahapola Merit Higher Education Scholarship for outstanding performance in G.C.E. (A/L) 2015, ranking 231st out of 32,393 students, honored by the Government of Sri Lanka.